William Bentley Papers MS009
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
William Bentley Papers
1783 -- 1819
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Bentley, William
MS009
8.53 Linear Feet 6 letter size document boxes, 4 record cartons, 1 half letter size document box, and 1 oversize box.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into one series.
Scope and Contents
There are over one thousand sermons in the collection along with a few devotional exercises, miscellaneous manuscripts and bound volumes. The handwritten sermons are arranged numerically (essentially chronologically) as numbered by Bentley himself. They are on a variety of subjects. Bentley's diaries are not part of this collection but are in the collection of the American Antiquarian Society.
Biographical / Historical
William Bentley was born in Boston on June 22, 1759, the son of Joshua and Elizabeth Bentley. Very little is known Bentley's early life and childhood. At fourteen years of age Bentley went to Cambridge and entered Harvard College where he graduated with distinction as a member of the class of 1777. After graduation he spent a few years as a schoolmaster serving at the Boston Latin School. Later, he became preceptor of the North Grammar School, also in Boston. From the North School Bentley returned to Cambridge and Harvard, this time as a Latin and Greek tutor where he remained until 1783, when he received a call to the ministry. This call came from the East Church (Second Congregational Church) in Salem, Massachusetts. The East Society tendered Bentley the offer of a joint-pastorate with the Reverend James Diman. Upon meeting the requirements to the apparent satisfaction of all parties, Bentley was ordained on September 24, 1783.
From the outset, however, the joint-pastorate did not work out. Diman seemed to resent his junior colleague and neglected him both officially and privately. Bentley, aware of these slights, brought them to the attention of the congregation and gained some concessions. Any new-found harmony between the two pastors was short-lived, and the rivalry began anew. Rather than support the established pastor the congregation sided with Bentley. Barely two years after Bentley's ordination Diman's association with East Church ended. He was dismissed, and William Bentley became sole pastor. He held that post until his death over thirty years later.
While principally a man of religion Bentley also established himself in secular affairs in Salem. He took a great interest in political, commercial and social events of his town, his nation and the world. His diary attests to this and even today remains a valuable source of late eighteenth- and early nineteenth-century life in America. Bentley remained a serious scholar all his life and had one of the largest private libraries (over 4,000 volumes) and Persian, Arabic and Chinese manuscripts in the US of the time; he also collected natural history specimens and coins. He had a special facility for languages, he could communicate in over twenty, including classical, Near Eastern, and modern European, and spoke seven languages fluently. He numbered among his correspondents some of the more prominent contemporary scholars of Europe and America and wrote columns in the Salem Gazette and Salem Register from 1797 to 1817 touching on most major US and foreign issues of the time. His diaries were later published.
For all his devotion to scholarly pursuits and political and commercial matters, these were avocations. Bentley's vocation was religion, raised in the stricter doctrines of New England Puritanism, he soon found a more liberal brand of theology to his liking. Through study and meditation Bentley found himself becoming more and more a Unitarian. In fact he became one of the first American ministers to openly declare himself and he pioneered the rise of Unitarianism in Salem. Bentley opened his pulpit to nearly all denominations. In keeping with his Unitarian faith Bentley introduced a more liberal catechism and church music into his congregation and encouraged and supported the teaching of choral music to women.
In later years Bentley continued to amass honors. He was asked to become Chaplain of the United States Congress, and Thomas Jefferson offered him the presidency of the University of Virginia. Both of these offers he declined in order to remain with his Salem congregation. Shortly before his death Harvard honored Bentley with the doctor of divinity degree, a most cherished ornament to a theologian's career. However, because Bentley had been upset at not having received the honorary degree earlier he left his library to the American Antiquarian Society in Worcester, Massachusetts, and to the Allegheny College, rather than to Harvard.
Bentley died in Salem on December 29, 1819.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Bentley, William; Clergy -- Massachusetts -- Salem -- Archives.; Unitarianism -- Clergy -- Archives.; Bentley, William, 1759-1819 -- Archives.; Religion
- Sermons, 1783 -- 1819; MS009.001; 10.45 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains over one thousand sermons in the collection along with a few devotional exercises, miscellaneous manuscripts and bound volumes. They are on a variety of subjects. Bentley's diaries are not part of this collection but are in the collection of the American Antiquarian Society.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged numerically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Sermon 1 -- Epistle to Timothy, 4 Chapter, 8 Verse, MS009.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 2 -- Psalm 94.18.19, MS009.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 3 -- John XIII. 35, MS009.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 4 -- Corinthians XIII, Chapter 12, MS009.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 5 -- Psalm 136.1, MS009.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 6 -- Josiah IXIII, MS009.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 7 -- St. Peter's Second Epistle, III Chapter at 11 Verse, MS009.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 8 -- Psalm CL. Last Words, MS009.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 9 -- Phillipians in 4, 5 Verses, MS009.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 10 -- Mathew XI.5, MS009.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 11 -- Mathew Sixth 10.11, MS009.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 12 -- Numbers. XXXii. 23, MS009.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 13 -- Joshua XXIV. 15, MS009.001.001.00013 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 14 -- St. John IV. 2, MS009.001.001.00014 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 15 -- 15th Chapter of St. John's Gospel From the 2 to 6, and From the 12 to 16th Verses Inclusively, MS009.001.001.00015 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 16 -- Micah VI. 8, MS009.001.001.00016 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 17 -- Psalm XXXIX. 1, MS009.001.001.00017 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 18 -- Exodus XX. 8, MS009.001.001.00018 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 19 -- Timothy III. 16, MS009.001.001.00019 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 20 -- Proverbs XXX. 8, 9, MS009.001.001.00020 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 21 -- Thessalonians V. 17, MS009.001.001.00021 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 22 -- Luke XXIV. 34, MS009.001.001.00022 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 23 -- Psalm VIII. 1, MS009.001.001.00023 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 24 -- Estes V. 11, 12, 13 Verses, MS009.001.001.00024 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 25 -- Romans VIII. 14, MS009.001.001.00025 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 26 -- Hebrews X. 31, MS009.001.001.00026 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 27 -- John I. Epist. 5 Chap. 11 Verse, MS009.001.001.00027 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 28 -- Mathew VI. 6, MS009.001.001.00028 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 29 -- Timothy III. 16, MS009.001.001.00029 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 30 -- Genesis XXII. 2, MS009.001.001.00030 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 31 -- Romans IX. 3, MS009.001.001.00031 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 32 -- Corinthians IV. 5, MS009.001.001.00032 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 33 -- Corinthians I. 25, MS009.001.001.00033 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 34 -- Genesis i. 31, MS009.001.001.00034 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 35 -- John's Revelations, VM Chapter, 9th and 10th Verses, MS009.001.001.00035 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 36 -- Phillipians W. 6, MS009.001.001.00036 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 37 -- James, Chapter III, Verse 8th, MS009.001.001.00037 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 38 -- Untitled, MS009.001.001.00038 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 39 -- Timothy iii, 16, 17, MS009.001.001.00039 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 40 -- John I. Epistle. Chap V, 16, 17 Verses, MS009.001.001.00040 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 41 -- Mathew V. 21, 22 Verses, MS009.001.001.00041 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 43 -- Luke XV. 24, MS009.001.001.00042 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 44 -- Timothy 6. 12, MS009.001.001.00043 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 45 -- Jeremiah XLV. 5, MS009.001.001.00044 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 46 -- Jeb XXXIV 10. 15-20, MS009.001.001.00045 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 47 -- Josiah LXIV. 8, 9, MS009.001.001.00046 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 48 -- Psalm IV. 4, MS009.001.001.00047 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 49 -- Corinthians XV. 47, MS009.001.001.00048 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 50 -- Jeb XXIX. 11-16, MS009.001.001.00049 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 51 -- Nehemiah VIII. 10, MS009.001.001.00050 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 52 -- Mathew 5. 14, MS009.001.001.00051 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 53 -- Luke XII. 32, MS009.001.001.00052 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 54 -- Luke II. 10, 11, 12, 13 and 14 Verse, MS009.001.001.00053 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 55 -- Corthinthians VI. 20, MS009.001.001.00054 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 56 -- Proverbs XVIII. 1, MS009.001.001.00055 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 57 -- Mathew V. 3, MS009.001.001.00056 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 58 -- Samuels III. 38, MS009.001.001.00057 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 59 -- Psalm XC. 12, MS009.001.001.00058 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 60 -- Mathew XXII. 42, MS009.001.001.00059 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 61 -- Kings IV. 7, MS009.001.001.00060 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 62 -- Kings V. 7, 18 Verses, MS009.001.001.00061 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 63 -- Psalm CIII. 14, MS009.001.001.00062 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 64 -- Peter V. 5, MS009.001.001.00063 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 65 -- Kings XII. 27, 28 Verses, MS009.001.001.00064 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 66 -- Thessalonians IV. 14, MS009.001.001.00065 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 67 -- Romans XIV. 16, MS009.001.001.00066 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 68 -- John XII. 42, 43, MS009.001.001.00067 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 69 -- Hebrews X. 5, MS009.001.001.00068 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 70 -- Chronicles V. 11, 12, 13, 14, MS009.001.001.00069 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 71 -- Deuteronomy XXi. 18-21, MS009.001.001.00070 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 72 -- Chronicles XXVIII. 9, MS009.001.001.00071 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 73 -- Jonah IV. 9, MS009.001.001.00072 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 74 -- Mathew VII. 9, 10, 11, MS009.001.001.00073 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 75 -- Acts 11. 42, MS009.001.001.00074 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 77 -- Psalm XLVII. 1, MS009.001.001.00076 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 78 -- Zachariah II. 1,2,3,4,5, MS009.001.001.00077 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 79 -- Mathew VI. 16,17,18, MS009.001.001.00078 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 80 -- Leviticus XXVII. 28,29, MS009.001.001.00079 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 82 -- Ruth I. 16,17, MS009.001.001.00080 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 83 -- Corinthians XIII. 5, MS009.001.001.00081 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 84 -- Genesis XLVII. 9, MS009.001.001.00082 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 86 -- Ezra VIII. 22, MS009.001.001.00083 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 87 -- Haggai II. 7, MS009.001.001.00084 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 88 -- Hosea II. 15, MS009.001.001.00085 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 89 -- Numbers XXXI. 15,16, MS009.001.001.00086 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 90 -- Mark VI. 26, MS009.001.001.00087 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 91 -- Daniel IV. 3, MS009.001.001.00088 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 92 -- Judges XIX. 20, MS009.001.001.00089 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 93 -- Mathew XXII. 11,12, MS009.001.001.00090 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 94 -- Obadiah I. 15, MS009.001.001.00091 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 95 -- Nahum I. 8, MS009.001.001.00092 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 96 -- Acts VII. 30, 31, MS009.001.001.00093 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 97 -- Corinthians IV. 21, MS009.001.001.00094 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 99 -- Proverbs XII. 22, MS009.001.001.00095 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 100 -- Proverbs XXIX. 23, MS009.001.001.00096 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 101 -- Ephesians VI. 24, MS009.001.001.00097 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 102 -- Amos IX. 5-10, MS009.001.001.00098 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 103 -- Kings IV. 26, MS009.001.001.00099 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 104 -- Ecclesiastes VII. 10, MS009.001.001.00100 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 105 -- The Song of Solomon VIII. 6, 7, MS009.001.001.00101 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 106 -- Thessalonians III. 9, MS009.001.001.00102 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 107 -- Colosians I. 26, 27, 28, MS009.001.001.00103 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 108 -- II John I. 4, MS009.001.001.00104 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 109 -- John VII. 17, MS009.001.001.00105 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 110 -- Habaccuc III. 17, 18, MS009.001.001.00106 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 111 -- Proverbs XXVII. 4, MS009.001.001.00107 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 112 -- Corinthians II. 3, MS009.001.001.00108 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 113 -- John I. 7, MS009.001.001.00109 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 114 -- Colosians III. 12, 13, 14, MS009.001.001.00110 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 115 -- Ephesians VI. 4, MS009.001.001.00111 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 116 -- Mathew X. 34, MS009.001.001.00112 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 117 -- Colosians III. 9, MS009.001.001.00113 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 118 -- Galatians II. 21, MS009.001.001.00114 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 119 -- Corinthians XIV. 40, MS009.001.001.00115 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 120 -- James V. 16, MS009.001.001.00116 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 121 -- Corinthians VIII. 4-7, MS009.001.001.00117 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 122 -- Kings VIII. 13, MS009.001.001.00118 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 124 -- Josiah XXXIII. 20, 21, 22, MS009.001.001.00119 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 126 -- Kings XVII. 4, MS009.001.001.00120 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 127 -- Hebrew XII. 2, MS009.001.001.00121 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 138 -- Corinthians X. 12, MS009.001.001.00122 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 139 -- Luke XVIII. 9, MS009.001.001.00123 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 140 -- Haiah XXXIX. 8, MS009.001.001.00124 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 141 -- Ephesians II. 2, MS009.001.001.00125 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 142 -- Jeremiah XXXV. 14, MS009.001.001.00126 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 143 -- Corinthians XV. 14, MS009.001.001.00127 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 144 -- Jeremiah XI. 16, MS009.001.001.00128 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 145 -- Corinthians X. 15, 16, 17, MS009.001.001.00129 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 146 -- Psalm CVII. 23, 24, MS009.001.001.00130 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 147 -- Samuel I. 23, 26, MS009.001.001.00131 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 150 -- Josiah XXX. 7, MS009.001.001.00132 (Box 1)
  - Sermon 151 -- Joel II. 17, MS009.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 152 -- Zephaniah I. 12, MS009.001.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 154 -- Psalm IV. 6, MS009.001.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 155 -- John IV. 24, MS009.001.002.00004 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 156 -- John II. 24, 25, MS009.001.002.00005 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 157 -- Ecclesiates VII. 14, MS009.001.002.00006 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 158 -- Mathew XII. 3, MS009.001.002.00007 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 159 -- Corinthians XI. 28, MS009.001.002.00008 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 160 -- Proverbs I. 7, MS009.001.002.00009 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 161 -- Samuel XXV. 17, MS009.001.002.00010 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 162 -- Mathew XXVIII. 20, MS009.001.002.00011 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 163 -- James III. 1, MS009.001.002.00012 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 165 -- Deuteronomy XI. 18, 19, MS009.001.002.00013 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 166 -- Mathew XI. 30, MS009.001.002.00014 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 167 -- Romans VIII. 38, 39, MS009.001.002.00015 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 170 -- Romans XII. 2, MS009.001.002.00016 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 171 -- Corinthians XIII. 13, MS009.001.002.00017 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 172 -- Corinthians III. 10, 11, MS009.001.002.00018 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 173 -- Mathew XXV. 41, MS009.001.002.00019 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 174 -- Proverbs XXI. 27, 28, MS009.001.002.00020 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 175 -- Genesis XVIII. 25, MS009.001.002.00021 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 176 -- Galatians III. 24, MS009.001.002.00022 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 177 -- Kings XXII. 7, MS009.001.002.00023 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 178 -- Exodus XVIII. 12, MS009.001.002.00024 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 179 -- John VI. 44, MS009.001.002.00025 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 180 -- Psalm XXIII. 11, MS009.001.002.00026 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 181 -- Acts VIII. 30, 31, MS009.001.002.00027 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 182 -- Luke XII. 15, MS009.001.002.00028 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 183 -- Ecclesiastes I. 9, MS009.001.002.00029 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 184 -- Mathew VII. 1-5, MS009.001.002.00030 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 185 -- John XVIII. 36, MS009.001.002.00031 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 186 -- Hebrews X. 25, MS009.001.002.00032 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 187 -- Luke XXIII. 28, MS009.001.002.00033 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 188 -- Psalm CXIX. 9, MS009.001.002.00034 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 189 -- Hebrews XIII. 18, MS009.001.002.00035 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 190 -- John XVI. 33, MS009.001.002.00036 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 191 -- Psalm XIX. 12, 13, 14, MS009.001.002.00037 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 192 -- Timothy VI. 3, MS009.001.002.00038 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 193 -- Ecclesiastes XII. 1, MS009.001.002.00039 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 194 -- Romans XIV. 10, MS009.001.002.00040 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 196 -- Mathew X. 16, MS009.001.002.00041 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 197 -- John III. 3, MS009.001.002.00042 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 198 -- Romans XII. 18, MS009.001.002.00043 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 199 -- Deuteronomy XXX. 11-16 and XXIX. 29, MS009.001.002.00044 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 200 -- Proverbs VIII. 30, 31, MS009.001.002.00045 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 201 -- Mark X. 21, MS009.001.002.00046 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 202 -- Mathew XXIII. 42, MS009.001.002.00047 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 203 -- Mathew XIX. 14, MS009.001.002.00048 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 204 -- Mathew XX. 21, MS009.001.002.00049 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 205 -- Peter II. 17, MS009.001.002.00050 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 206 -- Ruth I. 13, MS009.001.002.00051 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 207 -- Luke X. 38-42, MS009.001.002.00052 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 208 -- Peter II. 13, 14, 15, 16, MS009.001.002.00053 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 209 -- Ephesians II. 8, 9, MS009.001.002.00054 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 210 -- Peter III. 17, MS009.001.002.00055 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 211 -- Mathew I. 21, MS009.001.002.00056 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 212 -- John III. 19, MS009.001.002.00057 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 225 -- Psalm XXIV. 9, 10, MS009.001.002.00058 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 226 -- Luke XVIII. 1-8, MS009.001.002.00059 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 227 -- Mathew VI. 5, MS009.001.002.00060 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 228 and 229 -- Mark I. 12, 13, MS009.001.002.00061 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 230 -- Luke XIV. 1, MS009.001.002.00062 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 231 -- James III. 13, 14, MS009.001.002.00063 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 232 -- John II. 22, MS009.001.002.00064 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 233 -- Philemon 16, MS009.001.002.00065 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 234 -- Philippians I. 7, MS009.001.002.00066 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 235 -- Malachi II. 7, MS009.001.002.00067 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 236 -- Psalm CXLI. 5, MS009.001.002.00068 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 237 -- John XII. 14, 15, MS009.001.002.00069 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 238 -- Romans V. 12, MS009.001.002.00070 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 239 -- Mathew V. 43-48, MS009.001.002.00071 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 240 -- The Song of Solomon II. 10-13, MS009.001.002.00072 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 241 -- II Samuel XII. 22, 23, MS009.001.002.00073 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 242 -- Jonah IV. 11, MS009.001.002.00074 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 243 -- Mathew XII. 90, MS009.001.002.00075 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 244 -- Ecclesiastes XII. 12, 13, 14, MS009.001.002.00076 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 245 -- Acts XIII. 11, MS009.001.002.00077 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 246 -- Mathew XXVI. 22, MS009.001.002.00078 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 247 -- John V. 39, MS009.001.002.00079 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 248 -- Ecclesiastes V. 1, MS009.001.002.00080 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 249 -- John XIII. 3, MS009.001.002.00081 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 250 -- Luke XVIII. 13, MS009.001.002.00082 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 251 -- John I. 46, MS009.001.002.00083 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 252 -- Luke V. 26, MS009.001.002.00084 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 253 -- Corinthians III. 11-15, MS009.001.002.00085 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 254 -- Romans VIII. 29, 30, 31, 32, MS009.001.002.00086 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 255 -- Luke X. 29, MS009.001.002.00087 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 256 -- Luke XV. 7, MS009.001.002.00088 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 257 -- Philippians I. 10, MS009.001.002.00089 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 258 -- John XX. 17, MS009.001.002.00090 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 259 -- Philippians I. 27, 28, MS009.001.002.00091 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 260 -- Proverbs XIV. 9, MS009.001.002.00092 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 261 -- Romans VIII. 7, MS009.001.002.00093 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 262 -- Mathew VIII. 22, MS009.001.002.00094 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 263 -- Peter I. 8, 9, MS009.001.002.00095 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 264 -- Job XXI. 23, 24, 25, 26, MS009.001.002.00096 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 265 -- Acts XXIV. 13, 14, 15, 16, MS009.001.002.00097 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 266 -- Luke XVII. 32, MS009.001.002.00098 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 267 -- Proverbs XIII. 14, MS009.001.002.00099 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 268 -- Luke XXII. 31, 32, MS009.001.002.00100 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 270 -- Hebrews XIII. 4, MS009.001.002.00101 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 278 -- Jude 9, MS009.001.002.00102 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 277 -- Psalm XXVII. 10, MS009.001.002.00103 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 276 -- Psalm CXLIII. 2, MS009.001.002.00104 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 275 -- Mathew XX. 12, MS009.001.002.00105 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 274 -- Kings XXII. 19, 20, MS009.001.002.00106 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 273 -- Mathew XII. 9, MS009.001.002.00107 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 272 -- Acts III. 19, MS009.001.002.00108 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 271 -- Kings XI. 4, MS009.001.002.00109 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 279 -- Genesis XVIII. 21, MS009.001.002.00110 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 280 -- Luke XXII. 44, MS009.001.002.00111 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 281 -- Revelations VII. 15, MS009.001.002.00112 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 282 -- Ruth II. 15, 16, MS009.001.002.00113 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 283 -- Psalm L. 14, MS009.001.002.00114 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 284 -- Ephesians II. 14, MS009.001.002.00115 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 285 -- Romans VI. 21, MS009.001.002.00116 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 286 -- Acts IX. 22, MS009.001.002.00117 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 287 -- Genesis XIII. 36, MS009.001.002.00118 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 288 -- Deutoronomy XXXIV. 6, MS009.001.002.00119 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 289 -- Ecclesiastes III. 1, MS009.001.002.00120 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 290 -- Mathew XI. 28, 29, MS009.001.002.00121 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 291 -- Luke XX. 25, MS009.001.002.00122 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 292 -- Mathew XXIII. 37, MS009.001.002.00123 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 293 -- I Corinthians 25, 26, 27, MS009.001.002.00124 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 294 -- Luke XIV. 18, MS009.001.002.00125 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 295 -- Proverbs XXV. 17, MS009.001.002.00126 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 296 -- Luke VII. 9, MS009.001.002.00127 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 297 -- Job VI. 25, MS009.001.002.00128 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 298 -- Mathew XXIII. 15, MS009.001.002.00129 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 299 -- I Corinthians XI. 17, MS009.001.002.00130 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 300 -- James II. 1, MS009.001.002.00131 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 301 -- Luke XV. 20, MS009.001.002.00132 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 302 -- I Samuel XV. 22, 23, MS009.001.002.00133 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 303 -- Jeremiah VIII. 6, MS009.001.002.00134 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 304 -- II Timothy IV. 6, 7, 8, MS009.001.002.00135 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 305 -- Mathew XIII. 18-23, MS009.001.002.00136 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 306 -- I Epistle general of John IV. 1, MS009.001.002.00137 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 307 -- II Timothy III. 5, 6, 7, MS009.001.002.00138 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 308 -- Jeremiah VI. 16, MS009.001.002.00139 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 309 -- I Kings XIX. 11, 12, MS009.001.002.00140 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 310 -- Jeremiah XIII. 23, MS009.001.002.00141 (Box 2)
  - Sermon 311 -- Psalm LV. 14, MS009.001.003.00001 (Box 3)
  - Sermon 312 -- James I. 22, MS009.001.003.00002 (Box 3)
  - Sermon 313 -- James V. 19, 20, MS009.001.003.00003 (Box 3)
  - Sermon 314 -- Jonah I. 7, MS009.001.003.00004 (Box 3)
  - Sermon 315 -- Luke XXIII. 43, MS009.001.003.00005 (Box 3)
  - Sermon 316 -- Proverbs XXIII. 35, MS009.001.003.00006 (Box 3)
  - Sermon 317 -- Romans XIV. 22, MS009.001.003.00007 (Box 3)
  - Sermon 318 -- Acts X. 4, 5, 6, MS009.001.003.00008 (Box 3)
  - Sermon 319 -- Mathew XXIII. 29, 30, MS009.001.003.00009 (Box 3)
  - Sermon 320 -- I Samuel XXV. 35, MS009.001.003.00010 (Box 3)
  - Sermon 322 -- Hebrews XI. 4, MS009.001.003.00011 (Box 3)
  - Sermon 323 -- Psalm CXIX. 165, MS009.001.003.00012 (Box 3)
  - Sermon 324 -- Psalm CXIX. 97-104, MS009.001.003.00013 (Box 3)
  - Sermon 325 -- I Kings XXI. 20, MS009.001.003.00014 (Box 3)
  - Sermon 326 -- Job XIV. 10, MS009.001.003.00015 (Box 3)
  - Sermon 327 -- Psalm LXXXIV. 10, MS009.001.003.00016 (Box 3)